<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rspkt on Blog</title><link>https://blog.xil.se/author/rspkt/</link><description>Recent content in rspkt on Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 16:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.xil.se/author/rspkt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Is eval safe yet? Arbitrary code execution in Python</title><link>https://blog.xil.se/posts/is-eval-safe-yet-rspkt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.xil.se/posts/is-eval-safe-yet-rspkt/</guid><description>TL;DR Found use of eval in the Python gettext module. Bypassed weak security checks. Gained arbitrary code execution.
Background In Beyond PEP 8, an excellent talk by Raymond Hettinger, he jokingly comments that namedtouple is implemented using eval (or exec, to be exact), and that it&amp;rsquo;s defensible given the right circumstances. While this is sometimes true, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d clone the cpython repository and grep for any usages of eval-like functions.</description></item><item><title>Pwn2Win CTF 2016 Secret Accounts (Py 80) Writeup</title><link>https://blog.xil.se/posts/pwn2win-2016-secret-accounts-rspkt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 11:22:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.xil.se/posts/pwn2win-2016-secret-accounts-rspkt/</guid><description>Problem Description: Through many months of sniffing, we discovered a server running a software which the Club uses to manage information about secret bank accounts abroad. We even obtained its source code. We need to obtain access to the system in order to discover the real name of the owner of the account possessing the greater amount of money, in which bank it is, and the real amount. As you might expect, it seems that the Club has hunkered down to assert only authorized people, which really know what they are doing, are able to operate this system and to interpret information provided by it.</description></item><item><title>Pwn2Win CTF 2016 Dump (Forensics 50) Writeup</title><link>https://blog.xil.se/posts/pwn2win-2016-dump-rspkt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 01:14:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.xil.se/posts/pwn2win-2016-dump-rspkt/</guid><description>Problem Description: We know this dump was generated by a process which was executing as root in the computer, and that it was reading directly from a /dev device. Probably it is part of a keylogger module included in a rootkit which is being tested by the Club. Help us to unveil this message, allowing us to discover why they infected this specific machine.
Solution The dump file contained data that seemed to align well for 24 bytes, indicating that each record of the captured input was stored in some 24 byte datastructure.</description></item><item><title>Pwn2Win CTF 2016 Painel Message (Forensics 50) Writeup</title><link>https://blog.xil.se/posts/pwn2win-2016-painel-message-rspkt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 01:14:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.xil.se/posts/pwn2win-2016-painel-message-rspkt/</guid><description>Problem Description: The last month we gained access to a video portraying a Club&amp;rsquo;s electronics project. It looks like they want to insert this display into the the digital panels found in urban buses that circulate in large cities. We need to discover what this is all about.
Those who automate the ENTIRE resolution of this challenge deserve 20 bonus points. Show your code to a judge (@). ;)</description></item><item><title>Pwn2Win CTF 2016 Simple Cryptography (Crypto 60) Writeup</title><link>https://blog.xil.se/posts/pwn2win-2016-simple-crypto-rspkt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 01:14:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.xil.se/posts/pwn2win-2016-simple-crypto-rspkt/</guid><description>Problem Description: The club decided to evolve the security of communication for something more efficient and simple to be implemented &amp;hellip; simply too much!
The technique was reproduced in the message encoded below:
GA3TCYZRGU2DKXZXG5PTENZTHAZDSXZQHEYTKMJUGBSV6MBXGFSF6MTDGIYTGYJSMMZTIM3FL4YDOMLCL42GENJRGU2TIOBVGQ2WIXZRGBPTAZQ=
Add CTF-BR{} to submit the resulting hash.
Solution Figuring out the encoding scheme didn&amp;rsquo;t take many minutes. Noticing that the encoding alphabet seems to be a subset of Base64, we gave Base32 a shot. After decoding it, we were given the string:</description></item><item><title>Pwn2Win CTF 2016 Sequences (PPC 40) Writeup</title><link>https://blog.xil.se/posts/pwn2win-2016-sequences-rspkt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 00:44:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.xil.se/posts/pwn2win-2016-sequences-rspkt/</guid><description>Problem Description: Warm up for the next PPC challenges. The Club guys love sequences, and it is always good to know your enemy.
We will show you some sequences, and after each sequence you need to predict the values which correctly fill the asked positions. We ALWAYS adopt the convention that position 1 corresponds to the first number of the sequence.
Output sent by the server: Position - Sequence</description></item><item><title>Internetwache CTF 2016 The Cube (Rev 90) Writeup</title><link>https://blog.xil.se/posts/internetwache-2016-rev90-rspkt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 18:18:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.xil.se/posts/internetwache-2016-rev90-rspkt/</guid><description>Problem Description: I really like Rubik&amp;rsquo;s Cubes, so I created a challenge for you. I put the flag on the white tiles and scrambled the cube. Once you solved the cube, you&amp;rsquo;ll know my secret.
(rev90, solved by 232)
Attachment: rev90.zip
Solution In this task we were given a text-file containing the scrambling of a Rubik&amp;rsquo;s cube, as well as the different sides of the cube before it was scrambled.</description></item><item><title>SharifCTF 2016 Hack By The Sound (Misc 200) Writeup</title><link>https://blog.xil.se/posts/sharifctf-2016-misc-sound-rspkt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.xil.se/posts/sharifctf-2016-misc-sound-rspkt/</guid><description>Problem A well known blogger has came to a hotel that we had good relationships with its staffs.
We tried to capture the sound of his room by placing a microphone inside the desk.
We have recorded the sound about the time that he has typed a text in his blogg. You could find the text he typed in &amp;ldquo;Blog Text.txt&amp;rdquo;.
We reduce noises somehow and found that many characters may have the same keysound.</description></item></channel></rss>